晚安  好好梦
Good night and sweetly dreams.
不对
Oh, no.
晚安  好梦
Good night and sweet dreams.
小家伙  你怎么跑出来的
Pequeno, how you got out of cage, yeah?
停下  停下
Stop it, stop it, stop!
你在吼谁呢
Uh... who are you yelling at?
没谁  我就是写作卡住了
No one. I just...still have writer's block. That's all.
所以拿笔记本撒气吗
So, you're taking it out on your laptop?
不是  笔记本  是光标
No, not the laptop. The -- That cursor.
看它啊  在嘲笑我
Just look at it there, taunting me,
就那么一闪一灭的
just blinking on, off, on, off,
好像写畅销小说是什么简单的事
like it's so easy writing a best-selling novel.
你倒是试试看啊  光标先生
'Cause I'd like to see you try it, Mr. Cursor!
你倒是试试看啊  我们...
I'd like to see you try it! So why don't we --
这样吧  还是跟光标先生再见吧
You know what? Why don't we just say goodbye to Mr. Cursor?
这是什么  粉丝邮件吗
What is this, fan mail?
不是
Oh, not exactly.
还记得我前一阵曾上
Remember I went on "Good Morning America"
《早安美国》悬赏征集
a while back and offered a reward for proof
关于我失踪八周内
of anyone who knew what happened to me
究竟发生了什么的信息
during those eight weeks I disappeared?
但卡塞尔  这些信都是一年前的了
But, Castle, those letters are over a year old,
我们已经证明
and we've already proven
那些理论都是荒谬的
that all the theories were ridiculous.
你为什么又要重读
Why are you re-reading them?
想激发灵感啊
Looking to spark my imagination.
老实说  这些信都没什么创意
But, honestly, these letters are not very inventive.
要么是说我是被
They all either claim I was a victim of
政府阴谋迫害  就是被外星人绑架被"探测"了
a government conspiracy or abducted by aliens and probed.
这人还画了张我被ET外星人侵犯的示意图
This guy even drew a diagram of me being violated by E.T.
我需要灵感  贝克特
I need inspiration, Beckett,
尽管莱斯特对外星人解剖学的了解可圈可点
and although Lester's knowledge of alien anatomy is commendable,
但这不够
it is just not enough.
抱歉  稍等
Sorry. One second.
好吧  好的  我就到
Okay. All right. I will be right there.
你知道我也想带你去的
You know that I would love to take you, but --
但我们得继续假装分居
But we have to maintain the ruse of our separation
直到你抓到洛克塞特
until you capture LokSat.
我知道  只是
I know. I know. I just --
离了我的缪斯  我要写什么好啊  贝克特
What am I supposed to write about without my muse, Beckett?
我需要你  我是离了华生的夏洛克
I need you. I-I'm Sherlock without Watson.
不对  你是说没有夏洛克的华生吧
No, you probably mean Watson without your Sherlock
因毕竟  亲爱的  你才是作家
Because, after all, my darling, you're the writer.
好了  回见
Okay. I'll see you.
这样吧
Uh, you know what?
既然你这么想找案子来破
Why don't you just go to your P.I. Office
可以去你的私家侦探办公室
if you're so desperate for a case to solve?
或许阿丽克西斯和海莉
Maybe Alexis and Hayley have something
有能激发灵感的东西
that's worthy of... inspiration.
早啊  莱恩
Good morning, Ryan.
我看到了外面破碎的门
So, I, uh, saw the broken door outside.
-抢劫升级吗  -应该不是
- Robbery gone wrong? - No, we don't think so.
据动物园管理人员说
According to the zoo supervisor,
动物都在
all the animals are accounted for.
那是蛇钩吗
Is that a snake hook?
是的  看来被害人是被用这个打死的
Yep. Looks like our victim was bludgeoned to death with it.
好吧  被害人是谁
Okay. Who's the victim?
我们还不能完全肯定
Uh, we're not 100% sure yet.
动物园管理人员觉得应该是埃迪·拉米雷斯
The zoo supervisor thinks that it's Eddie Ramirez,
夜间动物看管人
the nighttime animal caretaker.
如果是  那么他是一名在美国
If it is, then he's an El Salvador native
住了五年的萨尔瓦多移民
who's lived in the States for the past few years --
等等  倒回去
Yeah, I'm sorry. Uh, can we go back?
为什么无法确认被害人的身份
Why are you having trouble I.D.ing the victim?
我们尚不能确认被害人的身份
We can't positively I.D. the victim yet
因为凶手把他的尸体丢进了
because the killer tossed his body into --
满是致命毒蛇的坑里
A pit filled with deadly snakes.
好吧  这真是没见过
Okay. Well, that's a first.
你无畏的领导人来了
Your fearless leader has arrived.
好诶  去把这些归档
Oh, yay. Now go file these.
看来生意不错
Well, I take it business has been good.
我们现在在查三起案子呢
Yeah, we're working on three cases right now.
企业渎职案  保险诈骗
Got a corporate malfeasance, an insurance fraud,
还有财政贪污
and a financial embezzlement.
知道这三起案子有什么共同点吗
You know what all three of those cases have in common?
都好无聊  拜托
They are all incredibly boring. You guys, come on!
-你们什么时候开始放低身段了  -什么
- When did you sell out? - Excuse me?
里克  你想说的  应该是
I think what you meant to say, Rick, was,
"多谢了  二位女士  把我的坑钱爱好
"Thank you so much, ladies, for taking my money pit of a hobby
变成了盈利的生意"
and making it into a profitable business."
我开这地方不是为了挣钱
I didn't open this place to make money.
而是为了令人激动的案子
I opened it for the exciting cases, you know?
两面三刀的女人  被盗古迹
The double-crossing dame, the stolen relic,
密室谜题
a locked-room mystery.
老爸  那都是40年代神秘小说的情节
Dad, you're just naming plots from 1940s gumshoe novels.
说起来  你不是该在写下一本
Speaking of, aren't you supposed to be writing
妮基·希特小说呢吗
your next Nikki Heat book?
如果能写就好了  拜托
Would if I could. Come on, guys.
把这企业什么的破案子丢在一边
Let's just ditch this corporate nonsense
找一个值得调查的案子吧
and find a case worthy of investigating,
有谜团  有大胆的人物
you know, with mysteries, with bold characters
离奇曲折的情节
and twists and turns and --
被杀男子被丢进毒蛇坑里
Murdered man ends up in a pit of deadly snakes?!
这...
Now, that --
这案子才值得一查
that is a case worth investigating.
你好啊  警监
Well, hello, captain.
很高兴你一个人来了
I'm glad you're alone.
我一直想说我对你非常骄傲
I've been meaning to say how proud I am of you.
为什么
For what?
当然是因为你跟卡塞尔先生分手了
For breaking up with Mr. Castle, of course.
现在你可以认识一个真正能欣赏你的人了
Now you're free to meet a man who can really appreciate you.
比如我弟弟  埃德加
Like my brother, Edgar.
你弟弟
Your, uh, brother?
我的胞胎兄弟
My identical twin.
你是双胞胎啊
Oh, there's two of you?
-我很乐意介绍你们认识...  -不用了
- I'd be happy to introduce you -- Yeah, no.
不不  不过  谢谢你  帕穆特
Uh, no, but, uh, thank you, Perlmutter.
我现在还没准备好开始约会
It's just that I-I'm not quite ready to date right now.
我听说你已经确认了
I understand that you have confirmed
被害人就是埃迪·拉米雷斯  是吧
that our victim is Eddie Ramirez, right?
是的  这是他的私人物品
Yes. Here are his personal effects.
死因是头骨遭受重击
Cause of death was blunt-force trauma to the skull.
从尸斑来看
Based on lividity,
死亡时间应该是昨晚9点到11点
I'd say it took place between 9:00 and 11:00 last night.
那么凶手把他的尸体丢进蛇坑
So, then, the killer must have dumped his body in the snake pit
一定是为拖延我们的调查
to slow down our investigation.
真是聪明
Genius plan.
卡塞尔先生  你来做什么
Mr. Castle, what the hell are you doing here?!
见到你我也很高兴  帕穆特
It is nice to see you, too, Perlmutter.
你看不出她已经不爱你了吗
Can't you see the lady doesn't love you anymore?
像个男人样  放手吧
Be a man. Walk away.
瞧  就因为你这样没脑子的小白脸
See, it's because of nitwit pretty boys like you
我弟弟埃德加那样的好男人才找不到...
that good men like my brother, Edgar, struggle to find --
帕穆特
Uh, Perlmutter,
能不能让我们单独待会儿
would you mind giving us the room just for a moment?
如果你需要  这儿有解剖刀和肋骨撑开器
There's a scalpel and a rib spreader if you need them.
帕穆特真是不喜欢我啊
Perlmutter really doesn't like me.
我现在也不喜欢你
Neither do I right now.
我知道  我就是想看看那些蛇
I know, I know, I just wanted to see the snakes.
自便  卡塞尔  都在动物园里呢
Help yourself, Castle. They are all at the zoo.
是吗  没带过来吗
Really? They're not here?
我以为会被算作证物呢
I thought they would be evidence or something.
不  但这个可能是
No, but this might be.
有人昨天给被害人发过短信
Someone sent the victim a text yesterday.
"我的钱呢  埃迪
"Where go my money, Eddie?
你欠了大钱  该还了
Yous owe huge. Paybacks time.
我有办法让你死"
I got ways for to get you dead."
发信号码屏蔽了
It was sent by a blocked number.
看看维克拉姆能不能追踪到
I'll see if Vikram can trace it.
"我有办法让你死"
"I got ways for to get you dead."
好特别的语法  好独特的结构
That's particular syntax, unique grammatical structure,
或许有什么文化重要性
perhaps denoting a cultural significance.
或许是自动更正的问题
Or maybe bad autocorrect.
不  贝克特  这不是失误
No, Beckett. This was no error.
这是选择
This was a specific choice.
是有条理的决定  是最基本的方言
It was a methodical decision, Dialectology 101,
而我恰巧又是英语专家
and I, being an expert in the English language,
很乐意帮你破解这语言的谜团
would be happy to help you solve this linguistic mystery.
卡塞尔  你不能参与查案
Castle, you're not gonna work the case.
所以  你还是回家去
So, why don't you just, uh, go back home,
我们今晚见
and I will see you tonight.
虽然我喜欢吻你  贝克特
While I do love kissing you, Beckett,
但在死尸面前
it's just a little creepy
感觉有点恐怖
when you do it in front of a dead body.
不太得体
It's...inappropriate.
警监  看我们在埃迪·拉米雷斯
Captain, check out what we found
床下发现了什么
hidden under Eddie Ramirez's bed.
一万美元  问题是
Ten G's. The question is
一个靠饲养蛇和蜥蜴为生的人
how does someone who feeds snakes and lizards for a living
怎么能筹到这么多现金
scrape together this much cash?
埃迪收到的那则威胁短信
Now, that threatening text that Eddie received
就是关于欠钱的
was about owing someone money.
如果这两者没有联系才怪呢
I'd be shocked if those two aren't related.
如果有  那我或许能帮忙
If they are, then I might be of assistance.
那则短信是由一部不可追踪一次性手机发的
Turns out the text was sent from an untraceable burner,
但短信发出时
but when the text was sent,
经过了一个无线网络
it had to go through a wireless network.
-你查到网络了吗  -是的
- Did you track down the network? - Yep.
是一家英语二外学校的
It belongs to an English-as-a-second-language school.
跟埃迪·拉米雷斯有什么联系吗
Is there any connection to Eddie Ramirez?
我跟老师谈过话  对方说
I spoke with a teacher who said
埃迪曾是班上学员
Eddie was a part of the class,
但昨天短信发出的时间他不在
but he was absent yesterday when the text was sent.
-好吧  去看看  -好
- All right, guys. Go check it out. - All right.
要从这里前往肯尼迪机场
To get to JFK airport from here,
你可以搭乘E列车
you can take the E train.
但由于你要赶不上航班了
But since you are late for your flight,
我建议你打的
I suggest you take a cab.
但由于你要赶不上航班了
But since you are late for your flight,
我建议你打的
I suggest you take a cab.
我们是纽约警局的
Yo, we're NYPD.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我们是纽约警局的
Yo, we're NYPD.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
埃迪的事真是令人震惊
This thing about Eddie is quite a shock.
同学们议论一早晨了
The students have been talking about it all morning.
我们了解到埃迪昨天没来上课
We understand that Eddie missed class yesterday.
你知道他是不是在回避另一名学生吗
Do you know if he was avoiding any of the other students,
或许是最近跟他有矛盾的人
perhaps someone he was having problems with?
埃迪  不  他人很好  很温柔
Eddie? No. He was a sweet man, a gentle soul.
大家都喜欢他
Everybody liked him.
不会是每个人
Well, not everybody.
这则短信是昨天上课期间发出去的
This text was sent yesterday during class.
知道这可能是谁写的吗
Any idea who might have written that?
"我的钱呢  埃迪
"Where go my money, Eddie?
你欠了大钱  该还了"
Yous owe huge. Paybacks time."
不知道  不好说
I don't know. It's -- It's hard to say.
我的学生英语都不太熟练
All my students are still learning English.
那我们得找你所有的学生问话
Well, then we're gonna need to talk to all your students,
一个个来
one by one.
那会比你想的要困难  警探
That's gonna be harder than you think, Detective.
大部分学生来自警察腐败的国家
Most of my students come from countries where the cops are corrupt,
他们不会想跟你们说话的
so they're not gonna want to talk to you.
老师
Look, teach.
我们不教你怎么动词变位
We don't tell you how to conjugate a verb.
你也别教我们怎么审讯嫌犯
Don't tell us how to interview a suspect.
是啊  我们会让他们开口的
Yeah. We're gonna get them to talk.
他们没有一个人肯开口吗
And you couldn't get any of them to talk?
哈维拿到了埃迪
Javi did get a contact number
萨尔瓦多亲戚的联系电话
for Eddie's next of kin in El Salvador.
是的  但家里没人
That's true, but there was no one home,
我们就留了言
so I had to leave a message.
警监  我们可以把学生都
Captain, we can drag each of the students
拉来审讯室  让他们紧张  交待实话
down into interrogation, sweat the truth out of them.
不行  如果他们已经很怕警察了
Uh, no. If they're already afraid of cops,
那只会让他们更加不愿配合
it's only gonna alienate them further.
但或许还有其他的办法
But there might be another way to do this.
你有什么想法
What do you have in mind?
别管了
Uh, don't worry about it.
你们去查查学生的生活
Why don't you guys dig into those students' lives?
显然  他们中有人隐瞒了自己对埃迪的真实看法
Clearly, one of them is hiding their true feelings about Eddie.
好的
All right.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
没干什么  看书呢
Nothing. Just reading a book.
你真觉得你可以凭语言学
Uh, do you really think you can figure out
查清是谁发的短信吗
who sent that text based on linguistics?
是的
Yeah, I can do that.
我只需要听到他们说话
All I have to do is hear them speak
就能找到对应的语法  怎么了
and I can match the syntax. Why?
你或许终究能参与此案了
Well, you might be able to work this case after all,
至少要卧底
at least in an undercover capacity.
是吗
Really?!
怎么说
How?
各位好
Bonjour, everyone.
我叫让-吕克·德拉库阿
Je m'appelle Jean-Luc Delacroix.
你好  让-吕克
Hello, Jean-Luc.
你好  让-吕克  欢迎来到我们
Hello, Jean-Luc. Welcome to our
英语二外课程
English-as-a-second-language class.
-非常感谢  先生  -你的口音真棒
- Thank you very much, monsieur. - That accent is fascinating.
你是哪里来的
Where are you joining us from?
魁北克  容基耶尔
Uh, Jonquière, Québec.
加拿大法国人
French Canadian.
-没错  -真棒  真棒
- Oui. - Wonderful. Wonderful.
你在那边是做什么的
And what do you do there for a living?
我就是...所谓的...主厨
I am, uh, how you say -- I am a chef.
-主厨  -是的
- A chef! - Oui.
真棒
Marvelous.
我们今晚就要进行国际美食节
We're having our international food celebration tonight.
真等不及尝尝你的地道的法国菜了
Cannot wait to sample some of your authentic French cuisine.
我也是
Oui. Me, too.
同学们  我们该
Well, class, it's time for us to
分小组讨论了
break out into our small-talk discussions.
大家起来  到处走动吧
Why don't we get up and circulate.
-那我...  -去吧
- I'll just, uh... - Please.
谢谢  谢谢  你好  我是让-吕克
Merci, merci. Hello, I am Jean-Luc.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
我是金贤周  韩国人
I am Kim Hyun-Joo from Korea.
就这样吗  别害羞啊
That is it? Please don't be shy.
跟我说说你自己
Tell me more about yourself.
随便说点什么
Anything?
好吧  好吧
Uh, okay. All right.
阿利斯泰尔·迪考伊
Alistair Durcoyne.
好  很好  认识你很高兴
Good. Okay. Very nice to meet you.
我是艾达·恩达伊  来自塞内加尔
I am Aida N'Diaye from Senegal.
幸会  我是让-吕克
Enchant? I am Jean-Luc.
你为什么来到美国
Ah, so, what brings you to America?
你在说法语  就像在塞内加尔那样
Ah, you are speaking French like back in Senegal.
但我们现在该说英语的  是吧
But we are supposed to speak English, oui?
我来到美国
I have come to America
因为我梦想有一日成为成功的画家
because it is my dream to become a successful painter someday.
真不错
Oh, very good.
嗯
Ah, oui.
你好  我是让-吕克
Hello. I am Jean-Luc.
我是艾哈迈德
I am Achmed.
我要去尿尿了
I urinate now.
好吧
Okay.
你好  我是让-吕克
Hello. I am Jean-Luc.
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, monsieur.
或许如果我可以看看
Perhaps it would help me to, how you say,
其他同学的作业
catch up with the rest of the class
能更好地跟上大家的进度
if I was able to look at their assignments.
没事的  让-吕克
You'll be fine, Jean-Luc.
事实上  你的英语已经很不错了
In fact, your English is already quite good.
打扰
Ah, excuse me.
有位学生需要你去看看
One of the other students would like your attention.
在后面  继续找
In the back. Keep looking.
我知道是谁发的短信了
I figured out who sent the text.
那人叫阿利斯泰尔·迪考伊
Guy's name is Alistair Durcoyne.
-你确定是他吗  -是的
- Are you sure it's him? - Yeah.
短信的语法结构
The grammatical structure in the text,
"我有办法让你死"
"I got ways for to make you dead"
跟他的家庭作业如出一辙
is a direct match to his homework assignment
他写道  "我去找啤酒喝"
where he wrote, "I went for to get some beer."
好样的  卡塞尔  我会让莱恩和埃斯波接手的
Good job, Castle. I'll have Ryan and Espo take it from here.
你要告诉他们我的贡献吗
Are you gonna tell them about my involvement?
我必须说
I have to.
我就说你是自己发现了二外课的事
I mean, I'll say you found out about the ESL class on your own
我也不知道你去卧底了
and that I had no idea that you were going undercover.
-你觉得他们会信吗  -我不知道
- You think they'll buy it? - Oh, I don't know.
你什么时候违背过我的意思
I mean, when have you ever gone against my wishes
插手调查啊
and interfered with an investigation?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
不用挖苦我嘛
No need for sarcasm.
你说句"会"就好了
All you had to say was "Yes."
我们刚跟
So, we just got off the phone
伦敦警察厅通过电话
with Metropolitan Police Service in London.
他们对你可有的是话要说  阿利斯泰尔
They sure did have a lot to say about you, Alistair.
多次因袭击和殴打被捕
Multiple arrests for assault and battery.
他们说你是一个高利贷
They said that you were an enforcer
"骨哥"吉米·巴瑞特的打手
for a loan shark named Jimmy "The Bones" Barrett.
你搬来美国
Did you move to America
然后自己创业了吗  阿利斯泰尔
and go into business for yourself, Alistair?
埃迪欠你钱吗  所以你才杀了他
Did Eddie owe you money? Is that why you killed him?
如果这人是英国来的
Hey, if this guy is from England,
为什么不说英语啊
why doesn't he speak English?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我知道该问谁
But I think I know just the person to ask.
他是个北方人
He's a Geordie.
纽卡斯尔人
From Newcastle.
虽然也算是英语
Though technically English,
但这种语言已经发展包含了
the language has evolved to include
一定特别的词汇和语法结构
a certain unique vocabulary and grammatical structure.
我可以翻译
I can translate.
你威胁要杀埃迪
You threatened to kill Eddie.
他说他给埃迪发短信
Oh, he says that he only sent Eddie the text message
只是因为他生气
because he was furious.
他开野鸡车
He drives a gypsy cab,
埃迪两晚前跟他借过
and Eddie asked to borrow it two nights ago.
次日早晨  阿利斯泰尔拿回野鸡车时
So, when Alistair got the gypsy cab back the next morning,
上面全是弹孔
it was riddled with bullet holes.
有人冲你的黑车开枪了
So someone shot up your cab.
这就是为什么他那么生气
That's why he was so livid.
埃迪答应会赔偿损失
Eddie promised that he would pay for the damage,
但接着就没去上课了
but then he didn't show up for class.
他以为埃迪是想躲着他
He thought that Eddie was trying to dodge him,
所以就发了则威胁的短信
and so that's why he sent him the threatening message,
但他说他不是真心的
but he swears he didn't mean it.
他只是很生气而已
He was just really pissed off.
就算阿利斯泰尔说的是真的
Um, let's assume that Alistair is telling the truth.
你知道他把你的车开去哪了吗
Do you know where he took your cab?
你知道他是去见什么人了吗
Do you know if he was meeting someone?
跟我们说说那辆野鸡车
So, tell us about your gypsy cab.
有定位系统吗
Does it have GPS?
有
Aye.
阿利斯泰尔的不在场证明证实了
Well, Alistair alibied out.
死亡时间内
He was blind drunk at a pub
他在一家酒吧喝得烂醉
during our time of death window.
那他的野鸡车呢
And what about his gypsy cab?
看来阿利斯泰尔说的是真话
Looks like Alistair was telling the truth.
不管埃迪把车开去了哪  有人企图杀他
Wherever Eddie drove that cab, someone tried to kill him.
看来这位温和的动物园管理员
Sounds like our mild-mannered zoo worker
惹了什么人啊
rattled a few cages.
其实  埃迪也没那么温和
Actually, Eddie wasn't so mild-mannered after all.
我联系上了他在萨尔瓦多的亲戚
I got in touch with his next of kin in El Salvador.
埃迪以前是个警察
Eddie used to be a cop.
等等  他是个警察
Wait. He was a cop?
我们怎么会才知道
Why are we just hearing about this now?
他在移民表格上隐瞒了
He lied on his immigration forms.
埃迪为什么不希望大家知道
Why wouldn't Eddie want people to know
他曾是警察
he's a former police officer?
我也觉得这很奇怪
I thought that was strange, too,
所以就调查了一番
so I did a little digging.
显然有传言说
Apparently, there were rumors
埃迪是一个黑警小队的一员
that Eddie was part of a corrupt police unit.
这些人被指
And these guys were accused of
敲诈罪犯  收受贿赂
extorting criminals, taking bribes.
我查了阿利斯泰尔野鸡车的定位系统
So, I've gone through the GPS on Alistair's gypsy cab.
看来埃迪只去了一个地方
Looks like Eddie only made one stop,
一个叫索尔达娜俱乐部的地方
a place called the Saldana Club.
好吧  我们对那里有什么了解
Okay. What do we know about this place?
经营者是何塞和弗兰基·索尔达娜
It's run by Jose and Frankie Saldana,
两人没什么分量
a couple of low-level players,
但他们有袭击和非法交易的前科
but they got priors for assault and trafficking.
另外  据说他们在俱乐部里贩毒
Plus, word is they deal drugs out of their club.
如果埃迪以前在
Well, if Eddie used to
萨尔瓦多敲诈罪犯
shake down crooks back in El Salvador,
或许他又对他们做了一样的事
maybe he was doing the same thing to these guys here.
而他们可能为此杀了他
And they might have killed him for it.
我们走
Let's go.
何塞和弗兰基·索尔达娜吗
Jose and Frankie Saldana?
是的  你们是谁
Yeah. Who's asking?
怎么回事  有人丢了颗手榴弹吗
So, what happened? Someone drop a grenade in here?
我们在重装修  喜欢吗
We're redecorating. You like?
看来你们惹了麻烦
Looks like you boys got into a little trouble.
嗯  攀岩事故
Yeah. Rock-climbing accident.
弗兰基忘记怎么系那种
See, Frankie here forgot how to tie
很复杂的绳结了
one of those fancy knots.
哎呦
Whoopsie.
那么跟埃迪·拉米雷斯毫无关系
So, it's got nothing to do with Eddie Ramirez,
就是你们冲他开枪的那人
the guy you took a shot at --
抱歉  我得找杯水喝
Sorry. I have to get water.
埃迪·拉米雷斯
Eddie Ramirez.
-没听说过  -是吗
- Never heard of him. - Really?
因为如果一个矮个50岁老头打了我的脸
Because if a short 50-year-old man broke my face
还偷了我一万块  我肯定会记得他
and stole 10 grand, I'd remember.
在想什么事吗
Uh, something on your mind?
他们在撒谎
They're lying their asses off.
那人  埃迪·拉米雷斯
That man, Eddie Ramirez?
-他来过  -怎么回事
- He was here. - What happened?
来的时候挺从容  紧接着
Came in all calm. Next thing I know,
他就把何塞和弗兰基打得满地找牙了
he's beating the crap out of Jose and Frankie.
逼他们往一个箱子里装钱
Forced them to fill up a briefcase with cash.
你都看到了吗
And you saw that all happen?
是的  埃迪准备离开时
Oh, yeah. As Eddie was walking out,
弗兰基从吧台下面掏出把枪来
Frankie grabbed a gun from under the bar,
蹒跚地走出去  冲他的车开了枪
hobbled out, and shot up the guy's car.
那昨晚呢
Okay, then what about last night?
他们有去对付埃迪  寻求报复吗
Did they go after Eddie, try to get their revenge?
不可能
They couldn't have.
他们那时都躺在医院呢
They were both laid up in the hospital.
今早刚出院的
Just got released this morning.
埃迪为什么要来这儿勒索他们的钱
Why would Eddie come here to shake them down for money?
我觉得并不是勒索那么简单
I don't think this was a straight-up shakedown.
我听到埃迪说他这是为了
I overheard Eddie saying that he was doing this
一个以前在这儿工作的女孩
for some girl who used to work here.
一个女侍者
A waitress.
什么女孩
What girl?
艾达
Aida.
你觉得是她杀了埃迪
You think she killed Eddie?
我们只知道索尔达娜兄弟俩有不在场证明
Well, all we know is that the Saldana brothers alibied out.
而她显然跟此事有关
And clearly she's wrapped up in all of this.
为什么找我来  我没干坏事
Why am I here? I've done no wrong.
我们只是有几个关于埃迪·拉米雷斯的问题要问你
We just have a few questions about Eddie Ramirez.
听着  艾达  我们知道索尔达娜俱乐部劫案的事了
Look, Aida, we know about the robbery at the Saldana Club.
三天前  埃迪在课后看到我在哭
Eddie saw me crying after class three days ago.
我...
I was, um --
因为被索尔达娜俱乐部解雇而非常难过
very upset because I was fired from Saldana Club.
你为什么被解雇了
So, why were you fired?
我在那儿干了两年
I work two years there,
但就因为我没有绿卡
but because I-I don't have green card,
何塞和弗兰基逼我拿出30%的工资给他们
Jose and Frankie make me give them 30% of my paycheck.
-他们在敲诈你  -是的
- They were extorting you? - Yes.
但因为学习英语二外
But from taking ESL class,
我有了自尊  要求他们给我钱
I get self-esteem and I demand my money.
于是他们就解雇了我
That when they fire me.
埃迪听说后  非常气愤
When Eddie heard, he was very furious.
他说他要去找他们
He say he would stand up to them
帮我拿回钱
and get all my money back.
好吧  如果是这样
Okay, if that's the case,
那埃迪怎么没把钱给你
then why didn't Eddie give you the money?
埃迪打算给的
But Eddie was going to.
他昨天早上打给我
He called me yesterday morning
说他为我拿到了一万美金
to say he got $10,000 for me.
我只需要等等
I just had to wait
因为他那天不能去上课
because he was not coming to class that day.
埃迪昨天为什么没去上课
So why wasn't Eddie coming to class yesterday?
他说他在帮另一个学生解决问题
He tell me he was helping another student with a problem,
一个危险的问题
a very dangerous problem.
等等  埃迪还在帮另一名同班的学生吗
Wait, Eddie was helping another student from the class?
-谁  -埃迪没说
- Who? - Eddie did not say.
但他跟我说时  听上去很紧张
But, uh, when he told me, he sound very nervous.
埃迪说  他发现了一个可怕的阴谋
Eddie say he uncover a terrible conspiracy.
什么样的阴谋
Uh, what kind of conspiracy?
埃迪没说
Eddie did not say.
那是我最后一次收到他的消息
That was the last time I hear from him.
如果埃迪还在帮助同班其他同学
If Eddie was helping other students in his class,
-那么...  -他是英语二外的伸冤人
- then that means -- - He was the ESL Equalizer.
-什么  -伸冤人
- Pardon me? - The Equalizer.
那个电视剧  还拍过电影
From the TV show. And the movie.
他是一位身手不凡的特工
He's a highly skilled operative
专为无法自卫的
who exacts vigilante justice
无辜者伸冤  伸张正义
for innocent people who can't defend themselves.
那个我知道  卡塞尔
Yes, I am familiar with it, Castle,
但罗伯特·麦考尔的角色是个好人
but Robert McCall's character was a good guy.
埃迪是个黑警
Eddie is a corrupt cop.
或许他在做弥补
Well, maybe he's making amends,
为曾经的罪孽赎罪
atoning for previous sins.
这不正是美国梦的精神吗
Isn't that what the American dream is all about,
-努力构建更美好的未来  -我只知道
- trying to build a better future? - Well, all I know is that
我现在想更好地立案
I'm trying to build a better case right now,
如果埃迪在帮助一位同学
and if Eddie was helping one of his fellow students
解决一个危险的问题
with a dangerous problem, then --
那他可能就是因此被杀
That might be what got him killed.
这是艾哈迈德·萨希德
And this is Achmed Sahid.
他两年前从
He immigrated to this country
巴基斯坦移民来
from Pakistan two years ago.
他曾是军方雷达系统工程师
He was a radar-systems engineer in the military.
艾哈迈德吗
Achmed?
他现在做什么
And what does he do now?
在切尔西摆热狗摊
He runs a hot dog cart in Chelsea.
这位是来自韩国的金贤周
This is Kim Hyun-Joo from Korea.
她是以互惠生签证来的  能待六个月
She's over here on an au pair visa for six months.
这位是厄米·冈萨雷斯  来自波哥大
And this is Ernie Gonzalez, originally from Bogotá.
这人以前是个律师
Now, this guy was a lawyer.
他现在给罗尼炸鸡屋
Now he's temping as a delivery driver
做临时送餐司机
for Ronny's Chicken Hut.
蒂亚戈呢
What about Diego?
蒂亚戈·洛佩斯来自墨西哥城
Diego Lopez from Mexico City.
他是一所小学的看门人
He works at an elementary school as a janitor.
他在墨西哥做什么的
And what did he do back home?
在一所小学当看门人
Worked at an elementary school as a janitor.
这些人从海外来到这个国家
These people all immigrated to this country
探索更好的生活
in search of a better life.
看起来埃迪是在帮他们实现
It looks like Eddie was trying to help them achieve that.
问题是我们怎么查出
The question is how do we figure out
埃迪还在帮助谁
who else Eddie was helping?
今晚是国际美食夜
Well, tonight is international food night,
让-吕克既然是大厨
and since Jean-Luc is a chef,
我要给他们提供法式美食
I will be plying them with French delicacies.
你的肉汁乳酪薯条
You packing poutine?
哈维尔  你要知道法裔加拿大人
Javier, I'll have you know that French Canadians
对作为巴黎文化的后裔感到非常自豪
are proud descendents of Parisian culture.
我要给他们带伯纳丁餐厅
No, I'll be serving them pastries
的油酥面点
from La Bernardin restaurant.
卡塞尔  那是全世界最好的
Castle, that's one of the premiere
法式餐厅之一
French restaurants in the world.
他们不外卖
They don't do takeout.
对让-吕克·德拉库阿也许如此
Perhaps not for Jean-Luc Delacroix,
但对理查德·卡塞尔会破例
but they will for Richard Castle.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
你们好  我的朋友们
Salut, mes amis!
-你好  让-吕克  -看上去很美味
- Bonjour, Jean-Luc. Hello. -Well, those look good.
警察找你问话啦
So, the police were questioning you?
是  他们想知道埃迪是如何帮助我的
Yes. They want to hear how Eddie was helping me.
但我不认为这是导致他被杀的缘由
But I-I don't think it's what got him killed.
警察有关于这案子的更多讯息吗
Did the police have any information about the case?
他们没告诉我更多
They did not tell me more.
埃迪有跟你说过什么吗
Did Eddie ever say anything to you?
不  没有
No. Nothing.
你想尝尝我的杂菜
You eat my japchae?
噢  当然啦
Oh, uh, uh, of course.
让-吕克
Jean-Luc?
怎么啦
What's wrong?
你不爱吃
You don't like it.
不  好吃极了
No, um, fantastique.
你说这个菜是来自哪里
Where did you say this dish was from?
我似乎在什么地方曾吃过
I think I've had it somewhere before.
我不太相信
I doubt that's true.
这是我老家的祖传秘方
It's a family recipe from my village.
非常棒  嗯  不好意思
Uh, very nice. Um, excusez-moi.
艾哈迈德  你没事吧  你看上去很低落
Achmed, are you all right? You seem upset.
你知道埃迪还在帮助谁吗
Do you know who else Eddie was helping?
是
Yes.
是我
Me.
我找了他帮忙
I-I-I came to him with a problem.
什么问题
What was the problem?
我楼里有个女孩失踪
A girl in my building is missing.
她是偷渡过来的
She is...undocumented.
失踪之前
Before she disappear,
她跟我说有人强迫她掏钱  不然对她下手
she tell me someone was forcing her to pay money or else.
你告诉埃迪这些了
And you told Eddie this?
是  他答应找到她
Yes. He promised to find her.
他死的天  我问过他
I-I ask about this the day he die,
埃迪说这事比他想象中危险得多
and Eddie say it was all more dangerous than he thought.
埃迪说他发现了一个可怕的阴谋
Eddie said he discovered a terrible conspiracy.
现在他死了  都是因为我
And now he's dead, all because of me.
不  艾哈迈德  不是你的错
No, Achmed. It is not your fault.
但兴许我能帮忙
But perhaps I can help.
那个女孩叫什么名字
Uh, what is this girl's name?
安妮塔·罗德里格斯
Anita Rodriguez.
我查了附近失踪人口  安妮塔·罗德里格斯
So, I looked into our missing neighbor, Anita Rodriguez.
因为她未登记
Now, because she's undocumented,
没有她的公众记录
there's next to no public record of her,
但是我发现了她在
but I did find out that she was working
一家清洁公司打黑工
at a cleaning company off the books.
一个半星期以前
Now, a week and a half ago,
她翘班没来  之后就再没露面
she missed her shift and hasn't been...seen...since.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
是的  我
Yeah, I --
今晚的英语二外课上发生了怪事
Something weird happened at ESL class tonight.
-怎么啦  -嘿
- What happened? - Hey!
我们刚刚从安妮塔·罗德里格斯的公寓回来
So, we just got back from Anita Rodriguez's apartment.
找到的指纹与前科犯匹配
We got a hit on a print.
马科·萨特
Marco Sutter?
是  他是科罗纳区的打手
Yeah, he's an enforcer from up in the Corona neighborhood.
有组织犯罪科有他的档案
Organized crime has a file on this guy.
敲诈  洗钱  蓄意攻击
Extortion, money laundering, assault with intent.
好  去把他带来
All right. Go pick him up.
马科·萨特
Marco Sutter?
纽约警察
Nypd.
待那儿别动
Hold it right there.
枪
Gun!
上吧
Let's go!
上
Go!
-纽约警察  -让我看到你的双手
- NYPD! - Let me see your hands!
马上让我看到你的双手
Let me see your hands right now!
把手从窗户里伸出来  马上
Put them out the window, now!
我这么认为
Here's what I think.
你要勒索一个弱势的外来移民
You tried to extort a powerless immigrant,
她付不起钱  你杀了她
and when she couldn't pay, you killed her.
当埃迪·拉米雷斯来找她
And when Eddie Ramirez came looking for her,
你把他也杀了
you killed him, too.
我要律师
I want a lawyer.
-嘿  -马科找了律师
- Hey. -Marco lawyered up.
但看看这个
But check this out.
我们在他钱包里发现了有趣的东西
We found something interesting tucked inside his wallet.
我们追踪到了
We traced it to a locker out
乔治·华盛顿大桥车站的储物箱
at the G.W. Bridge bus station.
我猜马科应该不会是把送洗的衣服放那里
I doubt Marco is keeping his laundry there.
兴许能成为证据来要他开口
Could be evidence we can use as leverage.
我们去查查
We'll look into it.
这一天过得
Oh, what a day.
可不是
Tell me about it.
条条大蛇  又遭枪击
Pit of snakes, getting shot at it.
感谢老天  快结束了
Thank God it's almost over.
我再受不了更多刺激了
I don't think that I could take any more excitement.
联邦调查局  趴下  趴下  趴下
FBI! Get down, get down, get down!
你知道联调局跟着案子多久了吗
Do you know how long the FBI's been on this case?
两年
Two years!
直到克罗克特和塔布斯搞砸我的监视行动
Before Crockett and Tubbs here T-boned my stakeout.
莱恩和埃斯波西托警探
Detectives Ryan and Esposito
在调查谋杀案  内皮尔探员
are investigating a homicide, Agent Napier.
就此监视行动  联调局
And no FBI alert came across my desk
并未事先提醒过我
about your precious little stakeout,
你干嘛不放低点姿态
so why don't you drop the attitude?
你怎么找到储物柜的
How'd you find that locker?
我们的谋杀嫌疑人被捕时带着钥匙
Our murder suspect had a key on him when we arrested him.
这个嫌疑人叫什么名字
And this suspect, does he have a name?
不  除非你先告诉我发生了什么
No. Not until you tell me what's going on.
我不能随便讨论
Oh, I'm not at liberty to discuss
有关此案的具体细节
the specifics of my case.
好吧
Okay.
那我想我们没什么好谈的了
Then I guess we're done here.
是马科·萨特  对吗
It's Marco Sutter, isn't it?
这是唯一一个可能有钥匙的人
It's the only logical person to have a key.
你们得放他走
You need to let him go.
不可能
Screw that.
他向我们开枪了
He shot at us.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你该在乎  因为如果这样我们都放他走
Well, you should, because if we let him go after that,
他很快就能想明白原因
he's gonna figure out why pretty fast.
我想马科只是你案子里的小鱼小虾
I'm guessing Marco's the low man on your totem pole
而你想通过追踪
and you're tracking the money
他交易中的赃款
from his shakedown operations
来牵出你们真正的目标
to get to your real target.
既然如此  何不让我们介入调查
So, why don't you let us in on the investigation
一起合作
and we can work this together?
没门  不过你说得对
That's not in my playbook, but you're right.
马科是个小角色
Marco is small potatoes.
所以你们继续关着他
So, you go ahead and keep him.
只是记住  我的联邦案件优先于你的谋杀案
You just remember my federal case trumps your homicide.
别耽误我们工作
So you steer clear.
你准备让那个小白脸压在我们上面
So, you gonna let that pretty boy steamroll us?
不  如果是马科杀了埃迪
No. If Marco killed Eddie,
那我们要把他
then we are gonna take him down
和与他相关的人统统拿下
along with anyone connected to him.
但我们得谨慎行事
But we have to tread lightly,
所以我要去联系一下联调局的朋友
so I'm gonna reach out to my guys in the FBI
看他们知不知道内皮尔在查什么
and see if they can tell us what Napier's up to.
卡塞尔
Castle.
出了什么事
Uh, what's going on?
你的护照在哪儿
Hey. Where's your passport?
我们得去一趟韩国
We've got to go to Korea.
为什么
Why?
因为我终于明白了
Because I finally figured it out.
我失踪的那段时间
My missing time?
现在终于都说得通了  大部分说得通了
It -- Now it all makes sense. It mostly makes sense.
等一下
Wait a minute, is this about
这是因为你在教室的时候发生的事吗
what happened in your classroom?
我今天吃到一种食物
I ate a dish today.
它触发了一段记忆
It triggered a memory.
我在韩国  周围都是韩国人
I was in Korea surrounded by locals,
而且我能看到那座寺庙
and I could see that temple.
通度寺
Tongdosa Temple.
在庆尚南道
It's in the South Gyeongsang Province.
我们知道那时候你在泰国
Okay, well, we know that you were in Thailand,
所以说去过韩国也说得通
so Korea's not a stretch.
我一定是在泰国之后去的
Yeah, I must have gone there right after.
但是为什么
But why?
我完全不知道
I have no idea.
我点了更多食物希望能唤起其他回忆
I-I ordered more food in hopes of jogging another memory.
但是没用  不过没关系
It didn't work, but that's okay.
等我们去了韩国  所有的
When we get to Korea, all the --
不不不  卡塞尔  我不会去韩国
No, no, no. Castle, I'm not going to Korea.
你说得对  我应该先去  这样
Yeah, you're right. I should go first. That way --
你也不会去
And neither are you.
我们还没有足够的信息
We don't have enough information yet.
这太危险了  你在泰国差点丢了性命
It's too dangerous. You almost got killed in Thailand.
你说得对
Yes, you're right.
那我就努力唤起更多的记忆
I'll just try to keep triggering more memories loose.
你想吃点泡菜吗
Are you in the mood for some kimchi?
因为我买了大概400刀的
'Cause I bought like $400 worth
那玩意我吃了就拉出去了
and...the stuff goes right through me.
目前为止  没有什么物证
So, so far, there's no physical evidence
能把马科和埃迪的谋杀联系起来
linking Marco to Eddie's murder.
你联调局那边的联系人有什么消息吗
You have any insight from your federal contacts?
只知道内皮尔探员
Only that Agent Napier
专攻欺诈和金融犯罪
specializes in fraud and financial crimes.
什么时候起金融犯罪先于谋杀案
Well, since when does financial crimes trump homicide?
从来没有  就我而言
Never, as far as I'm concerned.
谁是最性感的数码调查员
Who's the sexiest digital investigator alive?
我是不会说是你的  哥们
There is no way I'm saying you, bro.
你查到了什么
Okay. What do you got?
安妮塔·罗德里格斯
Anita Rodriguez.
她还活着
And she's alive.
她在德州  被关在一个私人拘留中心
She's in Texas, being held in a private detention center,
等待驱逐出境
awaiting deportation.
感谢上帝她一切还好
Thank God she's all right.
你到底是怎么找到她的
How on earth did you find her?
世界上应该有成千上万个安妮塔·罗德里格斯
There must be hundreds of Anita Rodriguezes out there.
她的指纹
Her fingerprints.
而且记录她为什么进那里的文件只有
And the paper trail for how she ended up at the facility
-薄薄几页  -故意为之吗
- is pretty thin. - Intentionally so?
也许  不过我有个可以追踪的名字
Maybe. But there was one name I could track.
杰森·科德维尔法官
Judge Jason Caldwell.
他签发的驱逐令  而且从他以往的记录来看
He signed the deportation order, and from his record,
这世上再没有什么比
there is nothing he likes in this world
驱逐外来人口出境更让他开心的事了
more than deporting foreigners.
但这并不能证明
But that doesn't prove
他和埃迪的谋杀有关
that he had anything to do with Eddie's murder.
是的  不过这个就非常有关系了
No, but this is pretty damn incriminating.
谋杀的前一天
The day before the murder,
我们的被害人在法院
our victim got in a shoving match with Judge Caldwell
和科德维尔法官发生争执
at the courthouse.
埃迪一定是把法官
Eddie must have connected the Judge
和马科的敲诈行为联系起来
to Marco's extortion scheme
然后去那里找他对峙
and gone down there to confront him.
如果埃迪威胁要揭发他们的合谋
If Eddie threatened to expose the criminal conspiracy,
那么法官就有很强烈的动机来杀他
the judge would have a strong motive to kill him.
我不明白
I-I don't get it.
移民敲诈的好处
The financial upside to extorting immigrants
应该没那么高
cannot be that high.
一个年薪六位数的法官为什么会参与其中
Why would a judge who makes six figures a year get involved?
我的想法是马科自己拿了所有敲诈的钱
My assumption is Marco kept the extortion money for himself.
法官能从中得到什么
What would the judge get out of it?
德州私人监狱的高额回扣
Huge kickbacks from a private prison in Texas.
根据科德维尔法官的财务情况
According to Judge Caldwell's financials,
他和艾尔帕索
he's got a sweetheart deal
一家经营拘留中心的公司交易地非常愉快
with a company that runs a detention center in El Paso.
他每填满一张床就有所回报
He literally gets paid for every bed he fills.
所以  马科敲诈移民
So, Marco shakes down the immigrants for money.
他们早晚会没有钱可付
Sooner or later, they run out of cash,
然后科德维尔就把他们丢到德州去
and then Caldwell ships them to Texas.
从中获利
And gets paid.
我恨这个人
I hate this guy.
我也是  我们把他带过来
Me too. Let's bring him in.
等一下  各位  他是个联邦法官
No, wait. You guys, he's a federal judge.
我们不能直接去抓他
We can't just go after him.
如果我们错了  那我们会
If we're wrong, then we'll...
等等  放大一下监控录像
Wait. Go full on the security cam.
各位  看那个门卫
You guys, look at the janitor.
他带着耳机
He's wearing an ear piece.
一个门卫为什么需要带耳机
Why would a janitor need an ear piece?
那个坐在长凳上看报纸的人也带着
So's the guy on the bench with the newspaper.
这说明那是联调局的监视组
Which means it's an FBI surveillance team
负责跟踪这个法官
following the judge.
他一定是联调局真正的目标
He must be the FBI's real target.
我们不能冲着这个人去  不能在联调局的眼皮底下
Oh, we can't go at this guy, not with the Feds watching.
内皮尔明确说明
Napier clearly stated
我们不能破坏他的调查
that we were not to step on his investigation.
纽约警局不能做
The NYPD can't.
但我可以
But I can...
让我朋友帮个小忙
with a little help from my friends.
科德维尔出发了
Caldwell is on the move.
正往法院那去
Heading to the courthouse.
真的很抱歉
I am so sorry!
太对不住了
Oh, a thousand pardons.
赶紧让开
Get out of the way.
你好
Hi!
你的宝宝真可爱
Your baby's so adorable.
你的也是
So is yours.
借过一下
Excuse me.
第二小组  目标正往你那去了
Team two, subject is coming your way.
对不起  我们帮不了你
Sorry. We can't help you.
货梯在大厅里面
Uh, service elevator down the hall.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
法官有坐电梯上楼吗
Hey, did the judge go up in the elevator?
我不知道
No entiendo.
该死
Damn it.
你先走
After you.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
这不对吧
This can't be right.
货梯在哪
Where's the service elevator?
我的天
Oh, my God.
你杀了我的未婚夫
You killed my fiance.
等等  我不知道你在说什么
Hold on. I-I don't know what you're talking about.
你是科德维尔法官
You are Judge Caldwell.
你谋杀了我的未婚夫埃迪·拉米雷斯
You murdered my fiance Eddie Ramirez.
我不知道那是谁
I-I have no idea who that is.
别再说谎了
Stop telling lies.
我知道就是你下的手
I know you are the one who did it.
女士听我说  你不想这么做好吗
Lady, listen, you don't want to do this, all right?
他  他不值得你这么做
He -- He's not worth it.
好  好
O-Okay!
我知道他
I did know him,
但我发誓我没杀他
but I-I promise I didn't kill him.
我没必要那样做
I didn't have to.
什么叫你没必要那样做
What do you mean you didn't have to?
那家伙是个警察
The guy was a cop!
他有很多仇人
He had enemies.
我敌人的仇人是...
A-And the enemies of my enemies were
什么
What?
这是什么  要给我下套吗
What is this, some kind of a setup?
你们到底是什么人
Who the hell are you people?
你  你最好告诉我发生了什么
You -- You had better tell me what happened
不然的话我就开枪了
or I'm going to shoot you.
你会才怪
The hell you will.
让他走吧
Let him go.
该死  差一点就成功了
Damn it. We were so close.
敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
你觉得是法官给埃迪在萨尔瓦多的仇家
Do you think the judge dropped a dime
通风报信了吗
to one of Eddie's enemies back in El Salvador?
问题是法官怎么联系上
Question is how did the judge find out
埃迪在萨尔瓦多的仇家呢
the names of Eddie's enemies back in El Salvador?
我不知道  但卡塞尔说
I don't know, but Castle said
法官提到了埃迪曾经是警察的事
that the judge referenced Eddie's past as a cop.
你们要不去查下
Why don't you guys see if you can find out
看能否找到在埃迪本国谁跟他有过节
who had a beef with Eddie back in his home country?
贝克特警监
Captain Beckett.
你知道你都做了些什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've done?
我想你会告诉我的
I have a feeling you're about to tell me.
我们就十分钟没看到科德维尔法官的踪影
We lose eyes on Judge Caldwell for all of 10 minutes,
然后他就取消了开庭
and the next thing you know, he's cancelled court
躲在了他的律师那
and he's holed up with his lawyer.
不好意思  这法官是谁
I'm sorry. Who is this judge, exactly?
少来这一套  警监
Knock it off, Captain.
我们知道你今天早上在调查科德维尔
We know you were on to Caldwell this morning.
我们调出了法院的监控录像
We pulled surveillance video from the courthouse.
你丈夫还有他那一伙移民另类
Your husband and his band of immigrant misfits
录像中都是他们的身影
are all over the footage.
好的  我会让我的人去问询他们
Okay, then I will make sure my guys question them.
你最好快一点  因为我正准备
Well, you better move fast, 'cause I plan on
让他们每一个人都被驱逐出境
having each and every one of them deported for this.
不可以  你要想找人负责你就冲我来
No, you want to go after someone, you go after me,
不关这些人的事
but leave those people alone.
他们干涉联邦的调查
They interfered with a federal investigation.
他们的朋友被杀害了
Their friend was murdered.
他们希望得到正义
They wanted justice,
这其中也包括生活工作在这个国家
which includes the ability to live and work in this country
不被政府任命的法官或是
without being victimized by a government-appointed judge
急于求成的联邦调查特工伤害的权利
or a power-hungry FBI agent.
杀害埃迪的凶手是科德维尔法官找来的
Eddie's killer was solicited by Judge Caldwell,
也就是说他就是此次谋杀案的共犯
which means he's complicit in the murder,
你帮我指认凶手
so you help me identify his killer
我们会把这个"好"法官送进联邦监狱
and we will put the good judge away in federal prison
让他在里面度过下半辈子
for the rest of his life.
看一下阿隆索·桑切斯
Meet Alonzo Sanchez,
锡那罗亚州贩毒集团的喽啰
foot soldier for the Sinaloa drug cartel
该集团在圣米格尔以外地区
based out of San Miguel.
他跟你的案子之间有什么关联
What's his connection to your case?
科德维尔法官48小时前办了加急签证
Judge Caldwell expedited his visa 48 hours ago.
直到你们提到埃迪·拉米雷斯我们才确定
We weren't sure why until you mentioned Eddie Ramirez.
他们之间有过过节
Turns out that they have history.
当埃迪在萨尔瓦多当警察时
Eddie killed Alonzo's brother, Mario,
他杀了阿隆索的兄弟马里奥
back when he was a cop in El Salvador.
敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
他肯定就是科德维尔法官说起的那个人
This must be who Judge Caldwell was talking about.
阿隆索要找埃迪报仇
Alonzo was out for revenge against Eddie,
法官当然很乐意帮忙
and the judge was all too happy to help.
阿隆索·桑切斯是在埃迪被害四小时前
Alonzo Sanchez landed at JFK
乘机降落在肯尼迪国际机场
four hours before Eddie was killed.
好了  我们似乎找到了凶手
Okay. Sounds like we have our killer.
现在我们只要在他回国之前抓到他
Now we just have to track him down before he goes back home.
可能已经太迟了
We might be too late for that.
他15分钟前就登机了
He boarded a flight 15 minutes ago.
-他已经在飞机上了  -那我们完了
- He's already in the air. - Well, then we're done.
我们现在没法抓到他了
There's no way we can get him now.
你们不可以  但是我行
Uh, you can't, but I can.
我是内皮尔特工
This is Agent Napier.
我需要让一架飞机返程
I need to turn a plane around.
阿隆索很遗憾你的飞机改航了
It's too bad your plane got rerouted, Alonzo.
但好的一面就是  我跟航空公司说了
On the bright side, I spoke to the airline,
你的飞行里程将会保留
and you're still gonna get the miles.
你根本就没证据
You got nothing on me.
我合法地来到这里
I was here legally.
你的旅行目的是什么
And what was the purpose of your trip?
拜访一位老朋友
Visiting an old friend.
拜访他还是拿他喂了蛇
Visiting or feeding him to the snakes?
什么
What?
算了吧阿隆索  别再装了
Come on, Alonzo. Drop the act.
我们知道你是为了埃迪·拉米雷斯而来
We know you came here for Eddie Ramirez.
他杀掉了你的兄弟
He killed your brother.
科德维尔法官  他帮你来到这里
And Judge Caldwell -- He greased the wheels to get you up here.
什么法官
Judge who?
我不知道你在说什么  先生
I don't know what you're talking about, man.
我们找到了那个出租车司机
We tracked down the cab driver
他在机场接你  把你送到了动物园
who picked you up from the airport
我们知道你杀了埃迪
and then took you to the zoo. We know you killed Eddie.
埃迪死了吗
Eddie is dead?
不是我干的
That wasn't me.
好吧  那个法官是联系我了
Okay, the judge reached out to me,
是的  我去动物园找埃迪了
and, yes, I went to the zoo to see Eddie,
但是我没杀他
but I did not kill him.
那你去那里干什么了
So, what did you come up here for, then?
友好地聊天
Little friendly chat?
缘分天注定餐厅来份冰心巧克力
Maybe a frozen hot chocolate at Serendipity?
我是抱着复仇之心去的
I came here with revenge in my heart.
我以为埃迪要为
I thought that Eddie was responsible
我弟弟的死负责
for my brother's death.
但是我搞错了
But I was wrong.
埃迪说服我他是在和我弟弟
Eddie convinced me that he had been working with my brother
秘密合作  暗中保护他
in secret, protecting him.
如果你正准备要杀埃迪的话
Eddie would tell you anything
他说什么都正常
if he thought you were gonna kill him.
你因为什么相信了他的话
so what made you believe him?
埃迪知道马里奥的一些私事
Eddie knew things about Mario
只有他身边亲近的人才会知道这些
that only someone close to my brother would know,
他的态度也不像是为了保命而说谎
and his attitude wasn't that of a man lying to save his life.
这话是什么意思
What do you mean by that?
埃迪痛恨自己在萨尔瓦多的所作所为
Eddie hated the man that he was back in El Salvador.
他保护我弟弟的所作所为让他很有压力
What he did to protect my brother weighed on him.
他对我说他鄙视我家人的所作所为
He told me that he despised everything my family stands for,
以及他的过往
what he used to stand for.
所以他来到了美国
That's why he came to America --
为了重新开始  在这里建立新生活
to start over, build a new life here.
他确实做到了  直到有人夺走了他的生命
And he did until somebody took it away from him.
阿隆索的不在场证明排除了他的嫌疑
So, Alonzo alibied out.
看来我们认为科德维尔法官参与其中是错的
Looks like we were wrong about Judge Caldwell's involvement.
不对  我们漏掉了什么
No. We're missing something.
埃迪和法官对质  第二天就被杀害了
Eddie confronted the judge, and the next day, he was killed.
我们知道不是法官杀的人
Well, we know it wasn't the judge.
他被24小时监控
He was under 24-hour surveillance.
再者说  他以为
And besides, he thought that
阿隆索会把他处理掉的
Alonzo was gonna take care of it.
埃迪和法官对质
Eddie confronts the judge.
12小时之后  阿隆索就持着合法签证上了飞机
12 hours later, Alonzo's on a plane with an approved visa.
法官是怎么知道阿隆索的
How did the judge even know about Alonzo?
-谁告诉他的  -你说的对
- Who told him? - No, you're right.
我们都不知道阿隆索
We didn't even know about Alonzo.
法官是怎么这么快发现的
How did the judge find out so quickly?
这场阴谋肯定还有其他人参与
There has to be someone else involved in this conspiracy,
和埃迪关系很近的人
someone close to Eddie.
和他关系近的只有英语二外班的那些人
The only people that are close to him are in the ESL class.
那么谁会杀了他呢
So, who would kill him?
我想我知道了
I think I know.
你知道这意味着什么吗  贝克特
And you know what this means, Beckett.
过了这么多年  我终于有机会说
After all these years, I finally get to say,
"我强烈谴责"[法语]了
"J'accuse."
现在我们重点讲动词
So, we're gonna focus in on the verbs.
现在  如果我们"以前去过"
Now, if we had --
让-吕克  你迟到了
Jean-Luc, you're late.
是的  先生
Ah, oui, monsieur.
不好意思
Pardonnez-moi.
没关系  坐下吧
That's all right. Have a seat.
实际上  埃莫森先生
Actually, Monsieur Emerson,
我能和你私下聊几句吗
if I could just have a word with you in private,
如果你愿意的话
s'il vous plait?
当然
Sure.
让-吕克  是你把他们带来的吗
Jean-Luc, did you bring these men here?
是的  他们和我一起的
Oh, yeah. They're with me.
他们是为了埃迪·拉米雷斯的谋杀案来逮捕你的
They're here to arrest you for the murder of Eddie Ramirez.
什么
What?
我们知道了你在和科德维尔法官合作
We know you were working with Judge Caldwell,
给他提供学校里的移民信息
funneling him immigrants from the school
以此在敲诈费里分一杯羹
in exchange for a cut of the extortion money.
你知道他们每个人面临的压力
You knew each one of their pressure points,
哪些人是非法移民
which ones were illegal.
太荒唐了
That's absurd.
是吗
Oh, is it?
那为什么你的学生中
Then why are so many of your students
有那么多都被私人拘留所扣押了呢
in those private detention centers?
太多了  不可能是巧合
Too many to be a coincidence.
真是个可靠的计划  谁会注意呢
It was a solid plan. I mean, who's gonna notice?
他们都孤身一人  徘徊在社会边缘
They're here alone, marginalized by society.
如果我在你的位置也会这么做的
In your position, I would have done the same thing.
-你不会的  -是啊  我才不会呢
- No, you wouldn't. - No, I would not.
-我是有良心的  -走吧
- I have a soul. - Come on. Let's go.
各位  我有好消息
Everyone, I have some good news.
安妮塔·罗德里格斯被释放了
Anita Rodriguez has been released.
联邦已经派人调查了
And a federal investigation has been launched
扣押她的拘留所
into the private detention facility that was holding her.
法官怎么样了
What about the judge?
你们的老师出卖了他  他把一切都坦白了
Your teacher sold him out. He confessed everything.
现在联邦调查局可以合法检举法官
Now the FBI can properly prosecute the judge,
正义得到了伸张
and justice has been served.
太好了  对不对
C'est magnifique, huh?
但是剩下的课谁来教我们呢
Oh, but, uh, who will finish teaching us now?
我在网站上看到是卡塞尔先生
I saw on the website it's Mr. Castle.
对不起
Uh, I-I'm so sorry.
我真不知道怎么会变成这样的
I have no idea how that got on there.
我知道  只是补位的卡塞尔不是先生
I do, only the Castle who will be filling in isn't a mister.
-是我  -真的吗
- It's me. - Really?
-干得漂亮  -谢谢  -宝贝我太为你骄傲了
- Nice work. - Thanks. - Darling, I am so proud!
她多可爱啊
Isn't she lovely?
好了大家
Okay, everyone.
-我们开始吃饭吧  跟我来  -是啊
-Shall we dine? Follow me. - Ah, yes.
各位  我们很开心
And, everyone, we are so glad
你们都能来我家做客
that you were all able to join us.
我们之前享受了你们家乡的美食
Now, we celebrated your food earlier.
现在轮到你们品尝
We think it's time for you guys to celebrate
美国菜了
some American food.
瞧瞧
And voil?
这是美国菜吗
This is American food?
看起来像是各国菜
It's very...international.
正是
Exactly.
这个国家就是移民建立的
And this country was founded by immigrants,
正是这些风俗文化
and it's those customs and cultures
塑造了今天的我们
that have shaped and molded us.
是你们
And you --
是你们让这个国家变得如此美好
And you are the ones that make this country great.
妈妈  我也说不了你这么好
Mother, I couldn't have said it better myself.
现在  尽情享用美食吧
Now, let's dig in.
快来
Yes, yes.
盘子在你们身后
Plates behind you there.
怎么了
What is it?
我不是在韩国
I wasn't in Korea.
我是在洛杉矶的韩国城
I was in Korea Town, in Los Angeles.
贝克特  我必须要去洛杉矶
Beckett, I've got to go to L.A.